Guide to the Dale R. Corson papers, 1935-2002.
Corson, Dale R. papers, 1963-2002.
- Series II. Articles and speeches
  - Speech - Reunion Forum, June 15, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Speech - Cornell Association of Class Officers, June 16, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Speech - Dedication of Bishop Memorial Plaque, June 16, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Speech - Dedication of the Vet College Res. Tower (Multicat), June 27, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Speech - Dedication of Lasdon House Student Residence (NYC), July 31, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Speech - Parent's Convocation, Aug. 26, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Speech - Student's Convocation, Aug. 29, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Speech - Senate Meeting, Sept. 10, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Speech - Inauguration of Robert A. Plane (Clarkson), Sept. 21, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Article - Graduate Education in New York State, Sept. 24, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - State of the U. Add. Trustee-Council Weekend, Oct. 11, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Speech - Entomology Centennial Symposium, Oct. 14, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Introduction - Sack Memorial Lecture (Dr. Giaever), Oct. 16, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Speech - University Faculty Meeting, Oct. 16, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Remarks - Committee for Corp. Support of Private U. Lunch, Oct. 31, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Speech - Tower Club Dinner, Oct. 31, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Talks - Middle Management and Press Conference re Financial Situation, Nov. 8, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Remarks - Dedication of Telescope - Arecibo, Nov. 16, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Talks - Financial Presentations to Faculty, Nov. 25, Dec. 2-3, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Statement - Before Pell Committee, Nov. 26, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Remarks - Howard W. Robinson Testimonial Dinner, Dec. 5, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Speech - NYS Agricultural Society, Jan. 8, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Memo - The Deteriorating Financial Scene, Jan. 15, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Remarks - Acceptance of Honorary Degree at Rochester University, Feb. 1, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Speech - Inaugural Seminar for Trustees at Rochester University, Feb. 1, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Speech - To University Faculty, Feb. 12, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Article - Further Thoughts on Unrestricted Inv. Inc., Handwritten Original, Mar. 4, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Article - Further Thoughts on Unrestricted Inv. Inc., Abstract, etc., Mar. 4, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Article - Further Thoughts on Unrestricted Inv. Inc., Bierman - "Price Level Adjusted Sheets: Cornell Univ. 1969-1974", Mar. 4, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - State of the University - Board of Trustees Meeting, Mar. 14, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Thoughts on Long Term Budget Equilibrium, Mar. 20, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Speech - To Sixth University Senate, Apr. 1, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Where Have the Good Times Gone?" Ithaca Rotary Club, Apr. 2, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Memo to Members of the Board of Trustees." Statutory College Budgets 1975-1976", Apr. 24, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Summary of the 1975-1976 NYS Budget and Its Impact on the Statutory Colleges of the State Univ. at Cornell, Apr. 29, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Remarks - "Higher Education in NYS," C.U. Council Administrative Board, May 2-3, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Remarks at opening Symposium - "Northeast Rails in Crisis", May 2, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Remarks Delivered to the University Faculty, May 7, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Greetings and Recognition of Initiates to Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society, May 9, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Remarks at Association of Systematics Collections, May 9, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Remarks at the Tower Club Dinner, May 14, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Remarks - Cornell Law School Convocation, May 24, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Speech - Medical College Commencement, May 28, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Remarks - Unveiling of Plaque in Memory of Frank Columbus, May 31, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - State of University, June 1, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Commencement Address, June 2, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Remarks - ROTC Commissioning Ceremonies, June 2, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Commencement Address to Kingsborough Community College, "The Length and Breadth of Education and Learning", June 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Remarks to 40 Year Class Dinner of the Class of 1935, June 13, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Remarks - Million Dollar Class Ceremony (Classes of 1928 and 1950), June 13, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Report to Alumni at Annual Mtg. of Alumni Assoc., June 14, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Remarks to the 50 Year Class Dinner of the Class of 1925, June 15, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Remarks at President's Convocation for New Students, Aug. 27, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - …On Behalf of Cornell, Sept. 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Statements before the Board of Regents Legislative Conference…on Behalf of ACUSNY, Sept. 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Statements before the Board of Regents Legislative Conference, Sept. 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Address - Joint Meeting of FCR and Univ. Senate, Sept. 24, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Papers Sent to Dean Levin, Sept. 29, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Remarks - German American Conference on Higher Education, Sept. 30, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Remarks - 25th Anniversary Dinner, C.U. Council, Oct. 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Address before the Joint Meeting of the Univ. Board of Trustees and C.U. Council, Oct. 11, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Remarks - Hans Bethe Retirement Dinner, Oct. 24, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Welcoming Remarks - SUNY Faculty Senate (See also SUNY), Oct. 24, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Statement before Pell Committee, Oct. 28, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Statement on Campus Safety and Security and Minority Education - Uris Auditorium, Nov. 14, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Remarks - Dinner in Honor of Ellis H. Robinson, Nov. 24, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Remarks - Mort Adams Testimonial Dinner, Dec. 3, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Remarks - Testimonial Dinner for Frederick G. Marcham, Dec. 8, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Remarks - Special Meeting of the University Faculty, Dec. 15, 197 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Remarks - Dinner Honoring Frank B. Ingersoll (Pittsburgh), Jan. 16, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Statement on Athletics - Presented to Trustees, Jan. 30, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - State of the University - Presented to Trustees, Jan. 30, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Statement on Self-Governance - Presented to Trustees, Jan. 30, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Comments about Cornell for National Geographic Magazine, Feb. 1976 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Guest Editorial in Experimental Mechanics Higher Education: Harshness and Hope, Feb. 1976 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Excerpts from American Physical Society Address, Feb. 2, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Address - Annual Meeting of the American Physical Society - "The Future of the Private University", Feb. 2, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Letter and Papers to Dannhauser (Not Sent), Mar. 1, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Remarks on Undergraduate Education at Cornell to Board of Trustees, Mar. 19, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Remarks - Cornell Bicentennial Convocation, Apr. 10, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Comments to FCR on Minority Affairs, Apr. 28, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Remarks - Tower Club Dinner, Apr. 29, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Statement (chronicle of news release) on Minority Ed., May 20, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Remarks - Law School Convocation, May 22, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Remarks - CUMC Commencement, May 26, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Commencement Salute to Graduates, May 28, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Remarks - ROTC Commissioning Ceremonies, May 28, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Remarks - Million Dollar Class Ceremony (1926), June 11, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Remarks - Class of 1916 Dinner, June 11, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Report - Annual Alumni Assoc. Meeting, June 12, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Notes for Remarks at Class of 1926 Dinner, June 12, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Greetings for 4-H Club Congress Program, June 29, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Remarks - President's Convocation for New Students and Parents, Aug. 31, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - "10 Points" - Deans of VP's Mtg., Oct. 12, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Speech to the University Senate, Oct. 12, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Address - Joint Meeting of Trustees and C.U. Council, Oct. 2, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Summary of Introduction to "Cornell in the 1970's", Nov. 1976 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Remarks - NASULGG Council of Pres. "Federal Support of Research and Graduate Education", Nov. 16, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Remarks - Buchanan Retirement Dinner, Dec. 7, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Greetings for New York State 4-H Congress Program, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Address - Annual Mid-Winter Meeting Cornell Assoc. of Class Officers, Jan. 29, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Remarks - North Carolina Ag. and Technical State Univ., Feb. 4, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Remarks - Cornell Campaign Kickoff - Palm Beach, Florida, Feb. 21, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Remarks - Cornell Campaign Kickoff - Los Angeles, CA, Mar. 24, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Paper Presented at the Circle - "Where Are We and Where Are We Going?", Apr. 18, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Notes for Remarks at Ag. Faculty Meeting, May 4, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Closing Address, Centennial Convocation, School of Nursing, May 5, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Remarks - Tower Club Dinner, May 10, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Notes - Remarks at Engineering College Advisory Council Meeting, May 13, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Remarks - Metropolitan New York Cornell Campaign Leadership Meeting, May 16, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Remarks - Cornell Alumni Assoc. of NYC/Cornell Women's Club of NYC Testimonial Dinner, May 17, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Remarks - Law School Convocation, May 21, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Remarks at Dinner given by Trustees and Pres. Councilors, May 25, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Remarks - Commencement - Medical College, Nursing, Grad. School of Med. Sciences, May 25, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Commencement Address, May 30, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Remarks - ROTC Commissioning Ceremonies, May 30, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Commencement Address - Elmira College, June 5, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Opening Remarks - Planetary Nebulae Symposium, June 6, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Remarks - Class of 1922 Dinner, June 10, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Remarks - Million Dollar Class Ceremony, June 10, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Remarks to 50 Year Class Dinner - Class of 1927, June 11, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Report to the Alumni at Annual Meeting of the CU Alumni Assoc., June 11, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Remarks - 1977 General Assembly of the Unitarian Universalists Association, June 21, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Remarks - Acceptance of 1977 Citation given by ACUSNY, Sept. 38, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Remarks - Dinner Honoring Leslie R. Severinghaus, Feb. 16, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Report to Trustees, Originals, Mar. 1978 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Remarks Written by DRC and Delivered by A.W. Brodeur, Mar. 3, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Letter to Pres. Councilors, Mar. 9, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Remarks - Memorial Service for D.K. Willers, Mar. 29, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Remarks - Deep Springs College, Apr. 4, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Remarks - Dinner Honoring Mr. and Mrs. Purcell, May 28, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Inflation and the Retired Professor, Reprints, July 7, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Washington is the Sunrise County - Or Is It?, Aug. 1978 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Remarks - Inauguration of Edmund T. Cranch, Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Oct. 20, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Remarks by Dale R. Corson, Memorial Service for Hazel Purcell, Cape Vincento, NY, Dec. 9, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Wire Ran Out, Dale R. Corson, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Speech - Saturday Night Club (Notes), Dale R. Corson, Jan. 27, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Notes - Frank Long Retirement Dinner, May 19, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Notes - Introduction of Pres. Rhodes, Class of 1929, 50th Reunion, June 8, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Notes - Talk to Class of 1919, 60th Reunion, June 9, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sunrise Article Correspondence, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Sun Rises in Maine, June 12, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Remarks at Memorial Service for James H. Smith, Jan. 31, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Talk - Extinctions, Mar. 19, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - The Sun Rises in Maine, Revisions, May 1981 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Talk to the Class of 1921, June 13, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Notes - Philips Lounge Dedication Talk, Oct. 17, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Physics Colloq., Mar. 15, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dedication of Dale R. Corson Hall, Sept. 9, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Corson - Mudd Dedication, Sept. 9, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Peace Studies Seminar, Jan. 26, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Research Club, Feb. 9, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hartman Birthday Celebration, May 20, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Symposium Honoring Eleanor Lambertsen CUMC-NYH, June 23, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Saturday Night Club "Censorship, Secrecy and National Security", Feb. 17, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Six Days in Spring - The Carpenter Hall Occupation, July 10, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Revitalizing the Scientific Enterprise," Syracuse Post-Standard, July 3, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - "Rochester Talk", Sept. 20, [1984] (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - DuBridge Symposium "The War Years", Sept. 21, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - "Physics in Sample Universities", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - AAAS Seminar - "Scientific Communication and National Security", Jan. 30, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - "China" Saturday Night Club, Feb. 16, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Secrecy, Censorship, and National Security, Student Pugwash Meeting, Mar. 22, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - AAPT - APS, May 17, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Wilkes College Commencement, May 19, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Introduction to Henry Guerlac's "History of Radar", Sept. 21, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Major Technical Problems Revisited, Sept. 28, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Trevor Cuykendall Memorial Service, Oct. 11, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Gramm Rudman - Hollings Conference on National Security, Feb. 26, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Engineering College Council, Apr. 5, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - K-Mart Annual Director's Dinner Remarks, May 27, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Wang Institute Commencement, Aug. 10, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - "Where Has Science Been and Where Is It Going?" Sigma Xi Symposium, Oct. 9, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Saunders Memorial Service, Jan. 31, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - "Dale R. Corson" (info for NAE Bueche Award, Apr. 5, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Saturday Night Club, May 2, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - "Where Has Science Been and Where Is It Going?", May 18, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - The United States Has No Adequate Mechanism to Set National Research Policy, May 18, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Report - Rutgers Promotion Review Committee, Aug. 1987 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Whither the Research University?, Dec. 5, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Whither the Research University?, Dec. 5, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Talk and Paper - Whither the Research University, Feb. 15, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Talk and Paper - Chinese Universities. City Club, Mar. 8, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - The Sun Rises in Maine, May 5, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Talk and Paper - RPI Key Executives, June 9, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Talk and Paper - Chinese Universities. Class of 1933, June 11, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Paper - "Engineering", Aug. 1988 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Speech for Bueche Award. Annual Meeting NAE, Sept. 28, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Predictions from Stars. Sat. Night Club, Oct. 1, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Talk - Cornell Council, Oct. 15, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - 20th Anniversary - R.R. Corson - Willard Straight Hall, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Notes - McConkey English Seminar, Ma. 14, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Report - Committee Social Implications of Science and Technology, Apr. 11, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - #477A Report - STS Committee on Soc. Implic., Apr. 11, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Berkeley Commencement, May 26, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Berkeley Commencement, May 26, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Talk, July 5, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - E. Hugh Luckey Memorial Service, NY Hospital Cornell Medical Center, Oct. 10, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Notes - U.S.-Japan Comm. on Scientific Coop., Co-Chairman's Meeting, Cornell, Oct. 24, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Universities Are in Trouble - Cornell Alumni News, Mar. 1990 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - James Krumhansl Symposium Retirement, Apr. 21, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - The Government-University-Industry Roundtable - ICSU Conf., Hungary, May 1990 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Notes - Retired Professor Association Talk, Sept. 24, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Talk - Floyd R. Newman Memorial Service, Dec. 7, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Circle Meeting - Waiting for the Big One, Feb. 18, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Talk - Cornell Alumni, VT, July 18, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Multidisciplinary Programs in Universities, Feb. 1992 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Talk - Ithaca Rotary, Feb. 19, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - "Reflections on the Bad Old Days", Mar. 1992 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Talk - Cornell Center for Environmental Research, Apr. 3, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Speech - Wells College Inauguration, May 2, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Talk - James Perkins Dinner, May 23, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Talk - E.F. Racker Memorial Service, June 20, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Talk - Harry Levin Memorial, June 21, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Notes - Chess Users Meeting, June 22, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Sixth United States-Japan Science Policy Seminar, Hawaii, Nov. 7-10, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Talk - Trustee Dinner, May 28, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Introduction - Carl Sagan Lecture, Oct. 13, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Talk - Gourdine Introduction, Oct. 20, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Talk - Mario Einaudi Memorial, Nov. 18, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Gourdine, "Flash," Dayton Ohio, Nov. 19-21, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Talk - Don Phillips Memorial, Dec. 8, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - AAAS, Atlanta, Feb. 17, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - The Big Crunch by David Goodstein, Mar. 8, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Talk - Circle World War II Radar, Apr. 1995 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Talk - Gould Coleman Retirement, June 9, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Taylor Retirement, May 19, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - E.P. Anniversary, Sept. 20, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Malott - Rotary, Oct. 16, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Finch Retirement, Dec. 5, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Photography and Me, Feb. 20, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Life on Mars - Scientific Symposium, May 19, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Boy Scout Award Dinner, May 20, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Kendal Science Seminar, May 27, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - The High Cost of Higher Education, May 18, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - James Perkins Memorial, Oct. 4, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - William T. Miller Memorial, Dec. 12, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Women's Club, May 1, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Faculty Forum, May 3, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - High Tenure Ratios Are Not Necessarily Bad (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Reference Materials for Speeches (Box 11, Folder 109-111)
- Series III. Research and course materials
  - Research Notes (Box 12, Folder 1-6)
  - X-Ray Defraction in Liquid Amalgams of Sodium and Mercury (Master's Thesis), 1935 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Thesis (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Kinetic Theory (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - War Dept. Employment Records, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Useful Curves (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Source Book for Low-Energy Particle Physics (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Radiation Lab Staff, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Army Air Forces, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Fermi Lectures - Los Alamos (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Security Clearance (Box 12, Folder 16-18)
  - Radar, 1944-1995 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Security Clearance, 1951-1956 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Project Vista (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Gamma + D —> Pi + D (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Notes, 1950's (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Satellites (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Sputnik, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 26A)
  - S+DS Lab (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Synchrotron (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Synchrotron Progress Reports, Nov. 1, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - The Cornell BEV Synchrotron, Dec. 1956 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Synchrotron Research Photographs (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - L.N.S. Synchrotron, 1946-1953 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Synchrotron Timing Circuit (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Multi-Scattering, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Meson Experiment (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Synchrotron Energy Calibration (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Collimater and Plate Holder (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - R-E-HP Nomographs (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Snyder-Scott Calc. (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Gamma + Rho —> Pi + Rho, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - CERN Conference, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Reviews of Nuclear Science (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Synchrotron, 1940's (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Magnet Data (Synchrotron) (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Magnet Data (Synchrotron) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Synchrotron Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Donut (Synchrotron) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Synchrotron (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Nuclear Plates (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mesons (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Nuclear Plate Work - Research File, 1949-1951 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Bethe Lectures - DRC's Notes (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Synchrotron Material, 1955-1957 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Talks, 1946-1957 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Western Reserve Talk, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Research Notes (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Research Notes (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
  - Misc. Research Notes, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Research Notes (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
  - Misc. Research Notes and Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Research Notebook, 1949-1951 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Research Notebook, 1951-1954 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies (Box 13, Folder 21-26)
  - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies - Progress Report, Dec. 1, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Drift Angle Computer - Designed by D. Corson (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Scientific Reprints, 1939-1957 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Freeman Dryson - Bethe Lecture Series, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Textbook: Electromagnetic Fields and Waves
    - Correspondence on Book (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Paul Lorrain Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Book Reviews, Adds, etc., 1988-1997 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Course materials
    - Physics 1A (U.C. Berkeley) (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Physics 2A (U.C. Berkeley) (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Physics 207 E + H, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Physics 2B, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Physics, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Physics 803-804 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Physics 620 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Physics 625, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Physics 860 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Physics 817-818-819 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Physics 624 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Physics 623 - Ohio State Theoretical Physics I, Thomas (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Physics 205 A, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Physics 64, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 10)